<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A declaration of the Commons assembled in Parliament concerning false rumours and reports, which an ill-affected party hath raised amongst divers of the inhabitants of Westmerland, Cumberland, Bishoprick of Durham, Newcastle, and Northumberland, against the Parliament, in perswading them, that the Parliament intendeth to take away the tenants rights of those counties.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Parliament. House of Commons.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 4 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B22333</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">19340831</idno>
  <idno type="VID">205469</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240880285</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing E2555</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">19340831</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B22333)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 205469)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1668:23)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A declaration of the Commons assembled in Parliament concerning false rumours and reports, which an ill-affected party hath raised amongst divers of the inhabitants of Westmerland, Cumberland, Bishoprick of Durham, Newcastle, and Northumberland, against the Parliament, in perswading them, that the Parliament intendeth to take away the tenants rights of those counties.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament. House of Commons.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[6] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by L.N. for E. Husbands and J. Frank,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Decemb. 17. 1642.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imperfect: print show-through.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Landlord and tenant --  Law and legislation --  Great Britain.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:205469:1"/>
            <p>A Declaration OF THE COMMONS ASSEMBLED IN PARLIAMENT, Concerning false rumours and reports, which an ill-affected party hath raised amongst divers of the Inhabitants of <hi>Westmerland, Cum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berland,</hi> Bishoprick of <hi>Durham, Newcastle,</hi> and <hi>Nor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thumberland,</hi> against the Parliament, in perswading them, that the Parliament intendeth to take away the Tenants rights of those Counties. LIKEWISE An Order for the Collectors of Purveyance of the severall Counties of this Kingdome, to pay no compositions for Purveyance for the Kings Houshold, but by the directions of the Committee of the Kings Revenue.</p>
            <p>
               <q>
                  <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <div type="license">
                           <p>Ordered, That this Declaration and Order be forthwith printed and published.</p>
                           <closer>
                              <signed>Hen. Elsynge, Cler. Parl. D. Com.</signed>
                           </closer>
                        </div>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
               </q>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed by <hi>L. N.</hi> for <hi>E. Husbands</hi> and <hi>J. Frank. Decemb.</hi> 17. 1642.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:205469:2"/>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:205469:2"/>
            <head>Die Jovis 15. Decemb. 1642.</head>
            <p>VVHereas it is informed, That some evill affected persons to the Peace of the Kingdom, have to the intent to withdraw the af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fections of a great number of the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitants of the Counties of <hi>West<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merland, Cumberland,</hi> Bishoprick of <hi>Durham, Newcastle,</hi> and <hi>Nor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thumberland</hi> from the Parliament, and to draw them to joyn with an Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my of Papists now under the command of the E. of <hi>Newcastle,</hi> raised false Rumors and Reports that the Parli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ament intendeth to destroy and take away the Tenant Rights of those Counties; Whereupon the Estates and livelihoods of many thousands of men depend. The Commons assembled in
<pb facs="tcp:205469:3"/> Parliament doe now declare, That they neither have nor ever had any aim or intention to destroy, weaken, or infringe any of the said Tenant Rights, or to prejudice the Tenants in their Customes or Tenures in the least particular; And they do au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thorize and require all the said Custo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stomary Tenants and others who are to pay any Fines or Rent to any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son or persons who have executed the illegall Commission of Array, or are or have been in actuall Rebellion a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst the Parliament, or contributed thereunto, to detain in their hands all such Fines and Rents, and to imploy the same for the Service and Defence of the said Counties and Kingdom, and in so doing they shall be protected therein by the said Commons, and dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged against their Landlords.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Hen. Elsynge, Cler. Parl. Dom. Com.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:205469:3"/>
            <head>
               <hi>Die Martis</hi> 13. <hi>Decemb.</hi> 1642.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>T is this day ordered by the Commons House of Parliament, That the Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lectors for Purveyance in the severall Counties of this Kingdome, shall pay no compositions for Purveyance for the Kings Houshold, but by the direction of the Committee of the Kings Revenue: And the Knights and Burgesses are to send down this Order into their severall Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties.</p>
            <p>And it is further ordered, That this Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der be forthwith printed and published:</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>H. Elsynge, Cler. Parl. Dom. Com.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="order_to_print">
            <pb facs="tcp:205469:4"/>
            <p>Ordered by the Commons in Parli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ament, that this De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claration and Order be forthwith printed and published.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>H. Elsynge, Cler. Parl. Dom. Com.</signed>
            </closer>
            <pb facs="tcp:205469:4"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>